<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Me on MacroMealey</title>
    <link>http://macromealey.tech/tags/about-me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Me on MacroMealey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 08:23:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://macromealey.tech/tags/about-me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://macromealey.tech/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 08:23:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macromealey.tech/about-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings and salutations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Shawn Mealey and I am a Engineer currently working for Rockets of Awesome. Based out of New York City, I have had the esteemed privilege to work on many projects with various clients over the course of my five year professional career.  I currently hold a bachelor’s of science degree in information technology from Alfred State College of Technology. I simply love all things technology and I am constantly on the hunt to improve my knowledge and understanding of new languages and processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created this blog as a place to organize my thoughts and to share my work in the hopes of helping fellow programmers. Currently my work involves primarily React work, though I have experience with Node.js, PHP,  and MySQL/PostGres. I am currently working on increasing my skills with Ruby on Rails, Python, and Go. If you ever have any suggestions for technologies that you think that I should check out, I am always open to exploring out new libraries and programming languages (time permitting of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my spare time, I like to exercise, read science fiction, do woodcraft, and get out into nature.  I also spend time with my beautiful fiancée Victoria and our cat Tallulah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to getting to know you better, and I hope you enjoy my site!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~Shawn Mealey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;figure-list&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure style=&#34;width: 370px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;../Shawn-Mealey.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shawn Mealey&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Shawn circa 2014&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure style=&#34;width: 370px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;../victoria_and_tallulah.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Victoria and Tallulah&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My Fiancée Victoria and our cat (kitten at the time of this picture) Tallulah&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>