<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MacroMealey</title>
    <link>http://mealeyst.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MacroMealey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 18:40:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://mealeyst.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New Look - New Feel</title>
      <link>http://mealeyst.github.io/article/Updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 18:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mealeyst.github.io/article/Updated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have noticed, my last post was back in October, and I said how I had hoped to do quick iterations on my site. Well, that plan backfired as when I showed my site to my peers, I received a deal of feedback, the majority being critical. I decided to start from scratch and re-do the theme of my site from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what has changed? The color scheme, the layouts, basically everything! One of the processes that I decided to implement this time was to utilize the Pattern Lab style of organization for my theme. I first tried to utilize the node version of Pattern Lab, but I found that there still seemed to be a few things that were still in flux with the codebase. I looked at other style guide generators and I settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://fbrctr.github.io/&#34;&gt;Fabricator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to be writing up a tutorial on how I integrated Fabricator with Hugo in due time, but needless to say the set up was fairly straight forward. I was extremely impressed with the flexibility that Fabricator offered. I was able to create, iterate, and update my style guide with ease. Some of the longer tasks with the new theme wasn&amp;rsquo;t the coding so much as the creation of icons and interactive form elements in Illustrator. If you want to take a look at the style guide of my site and see how it all comes together, feel free to check it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mealeyst.github.io/macromealey/styleguide&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a more robust theme created, I am going to be more active. I hope that you enjoy the new theme, feel free to peruse and reach out if you have any questions or comments. I have added some new features to the site as well such as the contact form and the progress tracker in the footer of the site. I will be writing separate tutorials for those features in short order as well, so keep an eye out for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://mealeyst.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 08:23:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mealeyst.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://mealeyst.github.io/Shawn-Mealey.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shawn Mealey&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Shawn circa 2014&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greetings and salutations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Shawn Mealey and I am a Engineer currently working for Rockets of Awesome. Based out of New York City, I have had the esteemed privilege to work on many projects with various clients over the course of my five year professional career.  I currently hold a bachelor’s of science degree in information technology from Alfred State College of Technology. I simply love all things technology and I am constantly on the hunt to improve my knowledge and understanding of new languages and processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created this blog as a place to organize my thoughts and to share my work in the hopes of helping fellow programmers. Currently my work involves primarily React work, though I have experience with Node.js, PHP,  and MySQL/PostGres. I am currently working on increasing my skills with Ruby on Rails, Python, and Go. If you ever have any suggestions for technologies that you think that I should check out, I am always open to exploring out new libraries and programming languages (time permitting of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my spare time, I like to exercise, read science fiction, do woodcraft, and get out into nature.  I also spend time with my beautiful fiancée Victoria and our cat Tallulah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://mealeyst.github.io/victoria_and_tallulah.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Victoria and Tallulah&#34; style=&#34;width: 350px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My Fiancée Victoria and our cat (kitten at the time of this picture) Tallulah&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to getting to know you better, and I hope you enjoy my site!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~Shawn Mealey&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>http://mealeyst.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 08:23:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mealeyst.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for taking the time to reach out to me! If you have any questions about my articles, tutorials, are looking to have me at an event, or have possible opportunities email is the best way to reach me. If you want to follow me on social media, I always try to follow back! I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Media:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/mealeyst315&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/100305425150670347075&#34;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pinterest.com/mealeyst/&#34;&gt;Pintrest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mealeyst&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;hr--dark&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Email Me:&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Site Builder</title>
      <link>http://mealeyst.github.io/lab/hugo-site-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 08:23:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mealeyst.github.io/lab/hugo-site-builder/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;prologue&#34;&gt;Prologue&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For quite a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a content management system that
was easy to use, but allowed for loads of customization. I had tried previously
to dive into the likes of WinterSmith not wanting to leave the comfort of
Node.js which I had taken a liking to. I found that while some of the static
Wintersmith was indeed easy to install and get set up, the time it took to do
customizations and set up things such as SASS compilation and minification were
taking me longer than I had hoped. It actually took me so long to do that I
instead opted to start my own static site generator that allowed for more
flexibility. The issue that I always had when building my own personal site was
the constraint of my good old friend Father Time. I would start getting into the
processes of building out my own static site generator and then get frustrated
with the fact that I was spending more time on trying to build out the project
than I was getting something out for people to read. I knew what I needed, but I
hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet found a solution that fit my needs, that is until I stumbled onto
Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did Hugo stand out to me? Well for starters, I loved the command line
interface. &lt;code&gt;hugo new site my-blog&lt;/code&gt; creates a new site, &lt;code&gt;hugo new
post/my-first-post.md&lt;/code&gt; will create a new post. Those commands were of course
awesome in their own right, but the ability to do: &lt;code&gt;hugo new
theme my-first-theme&lt;/code&gt; or the support out of the box for multiple content types
simply by defining a markdown file in the archtypes directory, making a new
directory for that content type and then simply running: &lt;code&gt;hugo new
relative/path/to/content.md&lt;/code&gt; needless to say I was quickly hooked! With my new
system in tow, I set out on building my personal site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Red Letter Day</title>
      <link>http://mealeyst.github.io/article/First/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 19:20:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mealeyst.github.io/article/First/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;today-is-a-red-letter-day&#34;&gt;Today is a Red Letter Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an awfully long time I have been wanting to create my own personal site, one where I could capture work that I had done both professionally as well as side projects to share with the world. I finally stopped hemming and hawing over how my site would look, feel, and function and decided to just get something functional up on the web and just iterate the heck out of it! If you are curious as to why I have both a &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; as well as a &lt;em&gt;laboratory&lt;/em&gt;, there was an organizational reason for it. I felt that the &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; could be more of a free-form area where I could collect my thoughts on technology, processes related to software development, and act as a coding diary of sorts. In this fashion, the blog is less structural and more open ended then the &lt;em&gt;laboratory&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;laboratory&lt;/em&gt; is relegated to small (or possibly large) project similar to the wonderful work done over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://tympanus.net/codrops/&#34;&gt;CoDrops&lt;/a&gt; where each post (or series of posts) will contain the resources needed to see a project all the way to completion. I felt that the separation would be easier for users to navigate and digest. Now that I have my site up and running there are a few side projects that I have been meaning to sink my teeth into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first project I was hoping to pick up is a professional side project that I have been discussing at work for a while. The idea is to hook up our React user interface to a separate rate repository who&amp;rsquo;s sole purpose is for the generation of a style guide. This repository would then be used as a dependency for the React components as well as our static Rails front end that we have for several of our landing pages. The idea is that the various front ends  would import styles, naming conventions, and possibly generate a barebones HTML/React components based on the elements generated in the style guide. For the style guide portion of the project I was looking to invest in &lt;a href=&#34;https://patternlab.io&#34;&gt;Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt;. The principles that Brad Frost has put out had intrigued me back in my contractor days at NorthPoint Solutions, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to implement his work ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second project that I have actually already started to work on, but have been failing to put as much time into is the Node.js base CMS &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mealeyst/TaurusCMS&#34;&gt;Taurus CMS&lt;/a&gt;. This has actually been a joint project with several other developers. The purpose of the project is not only to gain a deeper understanding of the inner workings of Node.js, but to also delve into the architecture and development of a full scale enterprise application. For the project I am looking to launch with a MVP product that contains:
* A database abstraction layer with a working Postgres implementation
* Command line tools to perform CRUD operations for content types as well as possible database management
* Use the Hapi framework to create an API to perform CRUD operations for content types
* Contain example Content Types and Taxonomies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While that MVP seems small (especially without a front end portion) the small amount of functionality that has been built already has taken a tremendous amount of research and trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the blog, I am looking to start up a &lt;em&gt;Ready for Rails&lt;/em&gt; development blog in which I do a weekly dive into Rails to take me one step closer to being a true start up unicorn, and finally be able to take an entire task from concept to completion at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always, I am going to be looking to improve the user experience on the site and make it so that the experience feels more tailored and unique to first time visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for now&amp;hellip; Onwards and upwards!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>