<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on MacroMealey</title>
    <link>http://macromealey.tech/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on MacroMealey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 18:40:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://macromealey.tech/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New Look - New Feel</title>
      <link>http://macromealey.tech/article/Updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 18:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macromealey.tech/article/Updated/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But little Mouse, you are not alone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In providing foresight may be vain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best laid schemes of mice and men&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go often askew,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And leave us nothing but grief and pain,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For promised joy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Robert Burns: To a Mouse - 1785&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-happened&#34;&gt;So what happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have noticed, my last post was back in October, and I said how I had hoped to do quick iterations on my site. Well, that plan backfired when I showed my site to my peers, I received a deal of feedback, the majority being critical. I decided to start from scratch and re-do the theme of my site from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what has changed? The color scheme, the layouts, basically everything! One of the processes that I decided to implement this time was to utilize the Pattern Lab style of organization for my theme. I first tried to utilize the node version of Pattern Lab, but I found that there still seemed to be a few things that were still in flux with the codebase. I looked at other style guide generators until finally settling on &lt;a href=&#34;https://fbrctr.github.io/&#34;&gt;Fabricator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-liked-about-fabricator&#34;&gt;What I liked about Fabricator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup&lt;/strong&gt; - Getting Fabricator setup within the theme structure of Hugo was as simple as running the command: &lt;code&gt;npm install fabricator --save&lt;/code&gt; in my theme directory. Fabricator already comes with a directory structure set up to quickly organize your assets, views, and materials (this is Fabricator&amp;rsquo;s method of organization). It made it so that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to think through the architecture of the theme, it was simply handled for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configuration&lt;/strong&gt; - The documentation that is provided on changing the default structure of Fabricator gave me exactly the direction I needed to implement my own custom version of Pattern Lab. I decided that I would stop at the template level of design as my pages are already being generated by Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template Language&lt;/strong&gt; - I found that the use of the HTML file extension just felt right at home with Hugo&amp;rsquo;s template language which is also uses the HTML file extension. The syntax that both use aren&amp;rsquo;t the same, but it was nice not to have to switch back and forth between handlebars and Hugo&amp;rsquo;s HTML templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabricators Theme&lt;/strong&gt; - I personally love the look and feel of Fabricator&amp;rsquo;s theme for viewing the toolkit styles and I like it just a little bit more than the minimal look and feel of PatternLab&amp;rsquo;s theme. When I got to show off my style guide, it feels more professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-don-t-like-about-fabricator&#34;&gt;What I don&amp;rsquo;t like about Fabricator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gulp&lt;/strong&gt; - Back when I was a consultant for NorthPoint Solutions, I was gung-ho to use Grunt, and then Gulp. After reading articles however on how to use NPM as a build tool, and even more recently on using webpack to compile assets, I feel like Gulp is a little heavy handed. Each time I run the Fabricator server (yeah it has it&amp;rsquo;s own server) it performs an &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; and then runs its compilation task. My thought is to possibly switch to a webpack task on my next iteration of the theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debugging Tools&lt;/strong&gt; - While I don&amp;rsquo;t like PatternLab&amp;rsquo;s theme as much as I like Fabricator&amp;rsquo;s, PatternLab has this nifty tool to switch between small, medium, large, and lastly a &amp;lsquo;disco&amp;rsquo; mode that widens and narrows the viewport so as to see how responsive design is being handled. Now Chrome of course has it&amp;rsquo;s own responsive tool that I made use of, but the ability to quickly see how elements react react when widened and narrowed right from the header of the style guide is a nice feature to have. It would be pretty easy to implement it via Javascript so I might submit a PR with that feature to the Fabricator repository in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;prologue&#34;&gt;Prologue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to be writing up a tutorial on how I integrated Fabricator with Hugo in due time, but needless to say the set up was fairly straight forward. I was extremely impressed with the flexibility that Fabricator offered me. I was able to create, iterate, and update my style guide with ease. Some of the longer tasks with the new theme wasn&amp;rsquo;t the coding so much as the design and creation of icons and interactive form elements in Illustrator. If you want to take a look at the style guide of my site and see how it all comes together, feel free to check it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mealeyst.github.io/macromealey/styleguide&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Red Letter Day</title>
      <link>http://macromealey.tech/article/First/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 19:20:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macromealey.tech/article/First/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;today-is-a-red-letter-day&#34;&gt;Today is a Red Letter Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an awfully long time I have been wanting to create my own personal site, one where I could capture work that I had done both professionally as well as side projects to share with the world. I finally stopped hemming and hawing over how my site would look, feel, and function and decided to just get something functional up on the web and just iterate the heck out of it! If you are curious as to why I have both a &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; as well as a &lt;em&gt;laboratory&lt;/em&gt;, there was an organizational reason for it. I felt that the &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; could be more of a free-form area where I could collect my thoughts on technology, processes related to software development, and act as a coding diary of sorts. In this fashion, the blog is less structural and more open ended then the &lt;em&gt;laboratory&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;laboratory&lt;/em&gt; is relegated to small (or possibly large) project similar to the wonderful work done over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://tympanus.net/codrops/&#34;&gt;CoDrops&lt;/a&gt; where each post (or series of posts) will contain the resources needed to see a project all the way to completion. I felt that the separation would be easier for users to navigate and digest. Now that I have my site up and running there are a few side projects that I have been meaning to sink my teeth into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first project I was hoping to pick up is a professional side project that I have been discussing at work for a while. The idea is to hook up our React user interface to a separate rate repository who&amp;rsquo;s sole purpose is for the generation of a style guide. This repository would then be used as a dependency for the React components as well as our static Rails front end that we have for several of our landing pages. The idea is that the various front ends  would import styles, naming conventions, and possibly generate a barebones HTML/React components based on the elements generated in the style guide. For the style guide portion of the project I was looking to invest in &lt;a href=&#34;https://patternlab.io&#34;&gt;Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt;. The principles that Brad Frost has put out had intrigued me back in my contractor days at NorthPoint Solutions, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to implement his work ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second project that I have actually already started to work on, but have been failing to put as much time into is the Node.js base CMS &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mealeyst/TaurusCMS&#34;&gt;Taurus CMS&lt;/a&gt;. This has actually been a joint project with several other developers. The purpose of the project is not only to gain a deeper understanding of the inner workings of Node.js, but to also delve into the architecture and development of a full scale enterprise application. For the project I am looking to launch with a MVP product that contains:
* A database abstraction layer with a working Postgres implementation
* Command line tools to perform CRUD operations for content types as well as possible database management
* Use the Hapi framework to create an API to perform CRUD operations for content types
* Contain example Content Types and Taxonomies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While that MVP seems small (especially without a front end portion) the small amount of functionality that has been built already has taken a tremendous amount of research and trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the blog, I am looking to start up a &lt;em&gt;Ready for Rails&lt;/em&gt; development blog in which I do a weekly dive into Rails to take me one step closer to being a true start up unicorn, and finally be able to take an entire task from concept to completion at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always, I am going to be looking to improve the user experience on the site and make it so that the experience feels more tailored and unique to first time visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for now&amp;hellip; Onwards and upwards!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>